Ivan Zolin

Software developer, Data Scientist

I have experience of commercial work as a software developer, data analyst and developer of machine learning methods. In particular, I have experience working in startups, in which I worked as an NLP developer, a Full stack developer, and a Tech Lead. I am proficient in basic mathematical sciences, Algorithms and Data structures, as well as programming languages: Python, C/C++, JavaScript.

zolin.work@yandex.ru

Saint-Petersburg, Russia

github.com/IMZolin

+79069363300



linkedin.com/in/ivan-zolin

WORK EXPERIENCE

Laboratory technician

Laboratory of Molecular Neurodegeneration at **SPbSTU**

07/2023 - Present Saint-Petersburg, Russia Research and development in the fields of immuno- and biotechnology, gene therapy

- Development of web interface for interacting with the API of PSF(methods to improve three-dimensional images from confocal microscopy using neural networks) applications.
- Development of automatic marking of spheres in the image to obtain an averaged sphere.

Contact: Ekaterina Pchitskaya - katrin.pchitskaya@gmail.com

Tech Lead, Software developer

Partner Finder (стартап)

02/2023 - 06/2023

Saint-Petersbura, Russia

- Creating a search engine for business offers (sklearn, nltk). Creating a recommendation system interface, combining it with other recommendations based on user information.
- Scraping the site getting test data for training (ads and users) in
- Development of the Ads component, working with the profile page(editor) on the frontend.

Contact: Egor Marin - egor.marin2017@yandex.ru

Fullstack developer

Interactiver (startup)

Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Builder for creating interactive educational tasks. LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/interactiver/

- Make upload files (the current HTML page) to create personalized jobs based on them.
- Learn about deploying the app on Heroku.

Contact: Viktor Katsman - vikto9494@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Applied Mathematics and **Computer Science**

Peter the Great St. Petersburg Polytechnic University (SPbSTU)

08/2020 - Present

Saint-Petersbura, Russia

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Web service for constructing PSF data of confocal microscopes with automatic ML segmentation of "spheres" in the image (04/2023 - Present)

- Tools: Computer Vision, ML, REST API, Python, Django, JavaScript, ReactJS, Docker, Redis, Nginx, Celery, Flower.
- The technology has received approval from SPbSTU for development fundina.
- Task 1: Develop a web interface for interacting with the backend of PSF applications.
- Task 2: Implement automatic marking of spheres in the image to obtain an averaged sphere (in the process of Bead extraction).

Maximization raft area of a given shape when the river turns the river by 90 degrees (+visualization, course work) (04/2023 - 05/2023)

- Tools: Python, pygame, numpy, LaTEX.
- GitHub: https://github.com/IMZolin/maximization-raft-area
- The shape of the raft: a rectangle with two equal isosceles triangles on two opposite sides.

ToDo List Telegram Bot (02/2023 - 04/2023)

- Tools: Python, aiogram, pewee, SQL, PostgreSQL, Docker.
- GitHub: https://github.com/IMZolin/Todolist-Telegram-bot
- Telegram bot, able to create, edit, delete, view to-do tasks, view completed tasks. The task consists of a description, date, time, frequency, attachments (files).

CERTIFICATES

Java. Basic course (08/2022 - 09/2022)

https://stepik.org/cert/1659594

Development of Android applications on Kotlin (09/2022 - 10/2022)

https://stepik.org/cert/1728735

Introduction to Linux (08/2023 - 09/2023)

https://stepik.org/cert/2175708

LANGUAGES

Russian Native or Bilingual Proficiency English

B1 (Intermediate)